Brandon Starkweather

East Syracuse, New York, United States



starkweather@me.com



linkedin.com/in/starkweathernow

Summary

I am currently working towards utilizing my Software Engineering degree to transition from Technical Support to Software Development. Please feel free to check out my Skills and approach me with offers for entry level software and web development work!

I have 10 years of experience as a technical support specialist with a particular focus on ensuring customers receive outstanding service. I strive to be a reliable and consistent employee, working well alone and as part of a team.

Experience



Charter Desktop Support Specialist

Charter Communications

Jan 2020 - Present (3 years 8 months)

Started as a contractor for Windows 10 migration project and transitioned to permanent employee after my efforts to successfully complete the project impressed the entire IT team.

Self-managed local IT Support Desk team member with a large area of coverage; working remotely and traveling via company truck to support the entire Central New York area.

Participated in an emergency pilot project designed to spearhead nationwide remote work at home initiative in response to Covid-19 outbreak.

Supported users remotely and in person during Covid-19 pandemic while adhering to strict CDC guidelines.

Implemented POS and retails systems in new Charter Mobile retail stores.

Provided local IT Desktop Support in a multi-purpose environment: 24 hour call center, operations management, field technicians and senior executives.

Replaced PCs for Windows users with minimal downtime and no loss of data.

Transitioned from ServiceNow ticketing system to Cherwell and assisted with opening tickets while maintaining SLAs.

Worked remotely after normal support hours for high escalation incidents.

Provided support for new remote call center workers with both software and hardware setup.

Provided support on location for several remote sites including various multi-purpose environments: IT Network Operations, Retail Stores, Field Technicians, Construction.

Responsible for safe operation and maintenance of the company truck to be able to effectively cover all of Central New York.

Maintained inventory of new, used and retired PCs, laptops, monitors and desktop equipment.

Recycled old inventory in bulk to assist with transition from Dell to HP.

Technical Environment:

Enterprise transitioning from Dell to HP with all desktops and laptops.

Win 7, Win 10, MS Office 2013, MS Office 2016, WebEx.

Panasonic Toughbooks, Mobile Hotspots, Android and iOS smartphones.

HP POS kiosk with mobile and touchscreen capabilities.

MS Active Directory, DameWare Remote Control.

Insight Migration Specialist

Insight

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 (3 months)

Contracted to Spectrum Charter for Windows 10 migration project.

Assisted users in transitioning from Windows 7 to 10 while maintaining their desktop environment with minimal downtime.

Traveled to several remote sites within the Central New York service area.

General local IT Help Desk duties: repairing laptop and desktop hardware, maintaining inventory and assisting with recycling efforts, restoring user access, troubleshooting software and hardware environment.

Technology Environment: MS Active Directory, SCCM DDI, Windows 10, Symantec VIP, Service Now, MS Office 2016



Technical Support Specialist

CBORD

Jun 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Provided troubleshooting and training for retail POS systems involving hardware and software.

Assisted Implementation department with installing and configuring new software and hardware.

Maintained strict industry standards when servicing customers with HIPAA & PCI Compliant concerns.

Designed and maintained customer facing technical support articles.

Worked remotely to support critical emergencies for on-call support.

Supported Technologies: Micros 3700 & 9700, Simphony 1.x and 2.x, Appetize POS, FreedomPay, MerchantLink and Elavon.

Technical Environment: MS Office 365, MS CRM, ShoreTel VoIP, OpenVPN, Bomgar, WebEx, Oracle MOSS

SALLY. POS Coordinator

Sally Beauty

Aug 2015 - Apr 2018 (2 years 9 months)

Provided technical troubleshooting and training for retail POS system involving hardware and software issues.

Coordinated with several different departments to ensure maximum POS uptimes.

Supported Windows laptop and Apple iPad users with software and hardware issues.

Managed 2 factor authentication tokens for remote VPN users.

Managed the 3 week training program for new hires coming into the POS Coordinator position.

Technical Environment: Citrix, Cisco VPN, WebEx, MobilePass SafeNet, MS Active Directory, ServiceNow, Box.com

K Retail Specialist

Kelly

Aug 2013 - Sep 2015 (2 years 2 months)

Assisted Apple Inc. customers with transactions, troubleshoot problems, answer questions about products and services available.

Consistently received high scores on customer surveys and quality assurance audits.

Assistant Webmaster

Reaper Miniatures

Mar 2012 - Nov 2012 (9 months)

Assisted with a variety of consumer-orientated projects by designing and developing website content within a custom LAMP environment.

Provided customer service and support through email.

Education

Western Governors University

Bachelor's degree, Software Development

Licenses & Certifications

CompTIA A ce - CompTIA

Issued Mar 2015 - Expires Mar 2018

- Project + CompTIA
- Advanced HTML5 & CSS3 Specialist Certification Partners
- QAMELOS ITIL Foundation Level AXELOS Global Best Practice
- User Interface Design Certification Partners

Skills

```
Web Development • Software Development • Project Management • MySQL • C++ • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • PHP • GitHub Copilot
```